Abdelrahman Ismail

Software Engineer

abdelrahman.e.ismail@gmail.com

+201025580308

May 13th, 1998 Sharqia, 44741, Egypt

Summary

Software Engineer with over five years of experience in software and web development, holding a Bachelor's degree in Computer Science from El Shorouk Academy. I have worked with diverse teams at Bright Future Education and Univortal, where I developed and implemented advanced software solutions..

Skills

- JavaScript, Python
- Langchain, Llama2
- Node Js, FastAPI, Django
- MongoDB, PostgreSQL
- Git/GitHub

Languages

- Arabic (native)
- English (Good)
- Germen (Good)

Links

Github:

https://github.com/abdelrahmanemadismail

Education

Bachelor's degree in computer science, Al Shorouk Academy (HICIT), Cairo Rank 6th at First Year

October 2020 - September 2024

High School, Hehia Secondary School for Boys, Sharqia

Work experience.

Backend Developer – 04/2023 – Present Univortal, Cairo

- Developed a RESTful API using Django,
 FastAPI, and PostgreSQL to enable users to interact with a dynamic Students management system.
- Worked on developing Al-driven programs to analyze student data and provide personalized recommendations, helping students choose the best universities based on their academic interests and future goals.

Software Engineer – 01/2020 – 03/2023 Bright Future Education, Cairo

- Developed and maintained the company's platform, creating scalable web applications using **Django** and **PostgreSQL**
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design and implement software systems tailored to solve specific business challenges

INVOLVEMENT

Head of Technical Team – 10/2022 – 09/2023 IEEE El Shorouk-Academy Student Branch

Programing Mentor – 10/2022 IEEE El Shorouk-Academy Student Branch

Technical Team Member – 11/2021 – 09/2022 IEEE El Shorouk-Academy Student Branch